PHILIP ROGERS

Java Developer / Software Engineer

philrogersuk@gmail.com +44 7791 470983 www.phil-rogers.uk LinkedIn: philrogersuk

Github: philrogersuk

CAREER SUMMARY

Vodafone // Nov 2011 - present Application Specialist

EE // Sep 2007 - Nov 2011 Genesys Developer

Hendon FC // Nov 1999 - present Web Developer

Avolites Ltd // Jun 2004 - Sep 2006 Software Engineer

Fixture Support Engineer

SKILLS

Strong Java 8 Software Engineer, experienced with Spring, Hibernate, AXIS and CXF for implementing custom solutions and SOAP/REST APIs.

Conversant in Voice UI design, VXML, GRXML and tuning solutions to improve performance based on statistical analysis

Intermediate knowledge of Jenkins, SonarQube, Docker, Mockito, Powermock, TDD and some AWS experience

Excellent communicator, capable of collaborating with all stakeholders within an Agile environment. Drove forward changes to adapt improved technologies to introduce CI in Vodafone Contact Centre.

CERTIFICATIONS

OCA Java SE 7 Programmer Genesys GCD8 - SDK Developer_

EDUCATION

MEng Software Engineering 2:1 UWA, Aberystwyth // 2002 – 2007

PROFILE

Experienced Java Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the telecommunications industry. Particularly skilled in Java, Spring, SOAP and REST Development and delivering custom solutions in PCI and CTI environments.

A strong and positive communicator and collaborator, driven to pushing teams forward to improve development, deployment and operational tools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

APPLICATION SPECIALIST

- Responsible for requirements gathering, design and build of complex IVR systems and back-end integration for Tesco Bank, Aviva, Legal & General and other high profile customers.
- Design and build of an in-house Java based framework for rapid, reliable and repeatable delivery of Cisco based IVR solutions.
- Conceived and implemented a CI stack provide automated and repeatable builds of Java solutions and code metrics. Developed a Powershell script to automate packaging of releases.
- Mentoring for colleagues learning Java, including one-to-one sessions, design and marking of coding exercises and supplementing of 3rd party learning tools.
- Required to design and build to global security and compliance standards, including PCI, GDPR and OFCOM requirements.

WEB DEVELOPER

- Development and support of <u>Hendon FC website</u> using Java 8 with Spring and Hibernate, currently hosted on AWS.
- Design and build of bespoke database schema and CMS, plus API integration with Twitter and bit.ly via REST APIs.
- Created a Docker based CI stack utilizing Jenkins and SonarQube.
- Maintenance of a Linux/Apache/Tomcat Server for 10+ years.

GENESYS DEVELOPER

- Lead Developer for custom Java integrations with Genesys Contact Centre solution, including reporting tools, ETL and UI changes.
- Technical lead for CRM integration and WFM upgrade projects.